# Morwarid Najafizada

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Data Analyst with three years of experience working as a Data Analyst. Strong problem-solving, analyzing, and researching skills. Experienced in modeling, interpreting, and reporting data. Recognized for maximizing performance by implementing and managing appropriate project analysis.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Data Analyst, StorageVault Canada Inc

Sep 2018 - Present

- Successfully interpreted data to draw conclusions for managerial action and strategy.
- Used statistical techniques for hypothesis testing to validate data and interpretations.
- Build reports and communicated the results and recommendations to the leadership team.
- Created static and ad-hoc deliverables to communicate performance and increased efficiency by 30%.
- Designed, coded, tested, maintained, and documented dashboard visualizations.

#### Data Entry Clerk, UN Association in Canada

June 2015 – Sep 2018

- Expanded the portfolio of sponsors by tracking and processing monthly changes and troubleshooting in the database.
- Generated regular reports and data exports, including tax receipts, gift acknowledgments, and membership lists.
- Processed contact and gift donation into Raiser's Edge a fundraising and constituent relationship management (CRM) system and saved the department 30 hours of manual work each week.
- Grew 20+ sponsors and donors by assisting with research.

#### **PROJECTS**

# **COVID-19** in the US Descriptive Analysis, CareerFoundry

Feb 2021

- Conducted an ad-hoc descriptive analysis of US COVID-19 metadata.
- Build a Linear Regression model to predict the number of deaths in the upcoming season and presented the results in dashboards and Excel reports.

## Instacart Grocery Basket Exploratory Analysis, CareerFoundry Dec 2020

- Performed exploratory analysis of the historical data of customers to derive insights and suggest strategies to better segmentation.
- Wrangled, aggregated, and merged the datasets to achieve better results and generated the results in reports and dashboards to communicate insights to stakeholders.

### Rockbuster Stealth Data Analysis Project, CareerFoundry

Sep 2020

- Performed an ETL process and extract data from multiple sources.
- Answered any ad-hoc business questions the management board had.
- Presented the SQL results to the business manager by creating compelling dashboard stories and reports.

### **US Flu Predictive Analysis, CareerFoundry**

June 2020

- Provided information to support a staffing plan using Pivot Table.
- Presented the conclusions, recommendations, and proposed next steps in final presentations and reports.

St. Johns, NL, Canada
+1 (613) 698 – 7059
morwarid1.github.io/
github.com/morwarid1
morwarid.najafizada@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/morwarid
public.tableau.com/app/profile/morwarid.najafizada

#### **SKILLS**

- SOL
- Python (Pandas, Geopandas, Numpy, Sci-Kit, Matplotlib, Seaborn)
- Interactive dashboards
- Tableau dashboards
- Power BI reports
- Data Analytics
- Data Modeling
- Data Transformation
- Data Visualizations
- MS Excel
- Business Requirements
- Hypothesis testing
- Machine Learning
- Linear Regression Analysis
- Data quality & integrity checks
- Data mining and wrangling

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Data Immersion Certificate**

CareerFoundry

Feb 2021

 Storytelling, SQL, Python, Data Ethics, Advanced Analytics, and Dashboard Design.

#### **Bachelor of Business Analytics**

University of Ottawa

Sep 2018 - May 2021

 Business Simulation Analytics, Business Forecasting Analytics, Business Optimization Analytics, Application of Business Analytics.

# **Data Analytics Certificate**

CareerFoundry

**June 2020** 

 Hypothesis & Statistical Analysis, Data Wrangling.